<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Biology and Bioinformatics Course Summary</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics Course Summary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Reticulate</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/09/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/09/test-post/</guid>
      <description>Throughout this semester in Computational Biology and Bioinformatics, we have been learning the ropes of basic coding in R and python. We have been using these skills to gain a better sense of how to wrangle/tidy data, how to visualize it to determine overall trends within the data, and how to best interperet these trends in a manner that serves to give us a better idea of the most relevant information to our probing questions or hypotheses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project_Two</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For this project, I decided to choose a more lighthearted dataset to analyze This dataset contains nine morphometric measurements of 101 mountain brushtail possums trapped at seven different sites across Austrailia. More information on my data can be found at https://vincentarelbundock.github.io/Rdatasets/datasets.html. My dataset includes 13 different variables. The ones I will be focusing on are the sex, site, total length, tail length, age, and belly girth.
 MANOVA I will be performing a MANOVA to determine the effect of capture site on the total length, age, belly girth, and tail length of a possum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Global Health Determinants</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing Determinants of Life Expectancy Across the World For this project, I was inspired by my Human Infectious Diseases and Clinical Bacteriology courses to study the effects of widespread vaccination coverage on global health. I found my first dataset on the WHO&#39;s official website https://apps.who.int/immunization_monitoring/globalsummary/timeseries/tscoveragebcg.html, and it breaks down vaccine coverage by vaccine type, country, and year. Next, I wanted to look primarily at life expectancy per country per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
